# **ALEX LEWIS**

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



# PERSONAL PROFILE

Throughout my young adult years I have developed a strong relationship with music and technology. After spending nearly a decade dipping my toes in many facets of the music business, I realized my expectations were far from the reality. I set a goal to find a new career that would be more engaging while still allowing me to continue practicing my creativity. Software development is a near-perfect balance between logic-based critical thinking and creative problem-solving. When I came to this realization, I was hooked. Thus spawned a new chapter of my life!

## **PROJECTS**

# Bookkeeper

Bookkeeper is a virtual library application that allows a user to track, notate, and share their reading progress. Originally, I put this application together in two weeks, mainly using React's JavaScript library. My goals were to gain a better understanding of state and data relationships by incorporating full CRUD functionality, as well as becoming more familiar with the React library, specifically React Hooks and props, all while maintaining a user-friendly experience.

# Project

(server-side capstone will go here)

# TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Nashville, TN Nashville Software School | Sep 2020 - Present

NSS in a six-month accelerated learning course that focuses on teaching HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and server-side fundamentals with Python and Django in a teambased environment.

#### Proficiencies:

- Building single-page applications with React alongside modern ES6+ JavaScript features and modular code
- Using Git and GitHub to manage version control of both individual and group projects
- Using GitHub Projects along with their issue tickets feature in order to manage projects
- Designing the structure of a database with the use of an entity relationship diagram (ERD)
- · Python, Django, SQL server

## **Group Projects:**

(server-side group projects will go here)

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ROUTE DELIVERY ASSOCIATE Nashville, TN Assured Xpress | Aug 2020- Jul 2021

- Responsible for loading the delivery van in an organized and timely manner
- Used a handheld device to safely travel along my specified route
- Delivered packages of various weight and size to residential properties and business while following customer directions
- Communicated with customers in order to solve issues related to package delivery

# STORE MANAGER Cincinnati, OH Jet's Pizza | Sep 2016 - Jun 2020

- Gained experience with managing a team in order to complete a day's work in an efficient manner
- Solved mistakes by communicating with co-workers and customers honestly
- Through prep-work, I learned the importance of planning and organization. These skills are crucial to being successful in almost any work environment

# **EDUCATION**

Nashville Software School Full-stack web development bootcamp

Columbus State Community College General education